Now so far we built a good enough program that can take user input and based on it.
It changes the MAC address of the interface that the user specifies to the MAC address that they choose.
What I don't like about it right now though is it looks a little bit messy.
And I think it can really use some refactoring.
Therefore I think this is a great opportunity to introduce you to functions.
Now functions are used everywhere in programming and we've actually used them in previous lectures even
without you thinking.
So for example when we used to use the input or the input that was a function that displays on screen
whatever we put in here and returns whatever the user inputs and then we used to capture that and store
it in a variable.
So what we mean by a function is it's a set of instructions that carry out a certain task like we've
seen before.
It can take an input.
So for example I can hear the input or the arrow input takes a string as input and displays it on screen
and it can return a value.
And again we've seen that this returns the value of whatever that person enters using their keyboard.
Now the reason why we use functions is because first of all they make our code look pretty and we'll
see that.
Now once we use it it also makes our code reusable.
So we've seen before that we use the input function twice in our code to ask for the interface and for
the MAC address without that function we would have had to write the code for the input function twice.
It also makes our code or makes programming more abstract because when we use the input for example
we don't even know how it works.
We don't know the code used in this function.
All we know is I need to give it a string.
This ring that I gave will be displayed on screen and then the function will work and ask the user to
enter something whenever the user enters something the function will give it back to me.
I don't know the code behind the input function itself.
Whoever wrote it wrote it very well.
And now all of us are using it.
So you need to use the same idea when you program.
So whenever you have a block of code in your program for example right here we have a block of code
that changed the MAC address.
Now we know that this code works very well and if we bundled this inside the function then we can reuse
this function any number of times even in the future if we write bigger programs and need to be able
to change the MAC address from within that program.
Then we can just call this function instead of having to type its code again.
Not only that but we can also bundle this in a separate file and then we can just import this the same
way that we import subprocess right here and call a marked change or function.
So we won't even have to worry about the code written in this function maybe in a year or two year or
five year time from now.
You want to be able to use a code that changes the MAC address.
You want to rewrite it.
You won't even have to remember how to change the MAC address.
All you have to do is just call the function that you created before.
So let's try and bundle all of this inside the function and use it from our code.
Now first of all you can define a function like so you just have to typedef followed by the function
name and it's a good idea to use meaningful function names.
So we'll call this function change Mark OK.
Now followed by this you need to put two brackets on between these two brackets.
We're going to specify the input that this function takes.
Again going back to the input function.
This function used to take a string as an input and then do stuff with it and display it on screen.
As we know so one who are defining our function here we need to specify what inputs it takes.
So we know in order to change the MAC address we need an interface and we need a MAC address.
So we're going to call these interface and new Mac.
Again the names here are completely up to you.
You can use any name that you find suitable You can use x and y if you wanted as long as they are valid
variable names.
Once you define the function name and the inputs that it takes all you have to do is just put call on
here at the end of the line and then hit enter.
Now you'll see automatically PI charme has indented this and put a tab for our cursor.
This is to show that everything that we're going to right now is going to be part of the change Mark
function and it's going to be part of this block of code.
Now the goal of this function to change the MAC address and we already know the instructions to change
the MAC address.
It's these instructions right here.
So I'm just going to cut them control X and paste them here what's very important to note is all of
the code that is part of this function need to be indented the same indention in here.
So all of the code that started here.
This is part of the normal Python program or script everything that's indented in here is part of the
change Mark function.
This is how Python separates blocks of code based on indention.
That's it.
Now our function is done we have a function called Change Mike.
It takes an interface and a new mark.
And whenever we call this function it will execute all the instructions in here.
So if we don't call this nothing is going to happen let me show you what I mean.
If I go down on my Python program and run the same command that we use to run before and let's change
that to 2 at the end.
You can see that we didn't get a print statement.
And if I do if config 88 0 you'll see that the MAC address did not change.
This is because we define the function here but we never use that in here.
So it's kind of similar to when we import a module but never use it.
So now what's happened is whenever you run Python it's going to read this read this read that this is
a function but not execute any of that and then it'll go back in here and start executing from the parser
it'll read the stuff that the person enters it and parse them to get the interface and all of that but
it'll never call change mark.
So all we have to do in here is call change mark now as you can see pie chart automatically knows what
I need to give to this based on the definition in here.
So telling me that I need to give it an interface and we know that the value for the interface is stored
in options dot interface.
So I'm actually going to use this directly and instead of using the interface variable in here.
So I'm just going to do options the interface and for the Mark we're going to use options that you Mark
and I'm going to delete these two lines because we don't need them.
They just are the value of options that interface and interface and options that Neumark any Neumark.
But now I'm using it directly I'm using options that interface and options that Neumark in the change
MAC function.
So now when Python reaches this line it's going to read OK.
This is a call for change Mark.
I'm going to use the interface as the first input here and use Neumark as the second input in here call
this function execute all of this code which will change the MAC address for me.
Let's test it out.
Going down run the same exact command that we did before but it didn't work.
Right now it printed the statement for me which means that it actually did get into this block of code.
And then if we do if config 88 0 you'll see that the Mac address the change to the Mac address that
I want now as you can see the code already looks neater.
And now every time I need to change the MAC address I won't have to use these four lines anymore.
All I have to do is just call change mag anywhere I want in my code.
Given the interface given the Neumark and it'll change it for me.
Not only that but in the future you'll learn how to put this in a special file and be able to call it
from any Python program that you want.
This will allow you to change the MAC address within any program that you write without having to worry
about the code used in this function something similar to the way that we use import prend row import.
And so one.